Previously on the show. Wolffy worked with the goats to catch his duplicates.
Episode sebelumnya. Wolffy bekerja dengan kambing untuk menangkap duplikat.
However, things kept going wrong at crucial moments.
Tapi situasi selalu salah di saat penting.
After many defeats, the goats and the wolf
Setelah kalah, kambing dan serigala memburu duplikat
Suddenly, a duplicate dropped into a waterspout
Mendadak, duplikat jatuh ke waterspout akibat serangkaian hal kebetulan.
What is going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Underwater Conspiracy"
Petualangan Langit Pulau Terbang: Konspirasi Di Bawah Air.
I can't become one again if one is missing.
Aku tak bisa menyatu jika tak lengkap!
What should we do?
Kita harus bagaimana?
Wolffy, let's go down to save that duplicate.
Wolffy, ayo turun untuk selamatkan duplikat itu.
Sure.
Tentu.
It's rare to see Wolffy so enthusiastic.
Sangat jarang melihat Wolffy antusias.
I don't want to be like this for the rest of my life!
Aku tak mau terus begini selamanya.
Come on, let's go down the waterspout in Magic Train.
Mari turun ke waterspout dengan Kereta Ajaib.
You're not driving Sirius?
Kau tak pakai Sirius?
A waterspout is so dangerous.
Waterspout sangat berbahaya. Bagaimana jika Sirius-ku rusak?
Magic Train...
Kereta Ajaib...
Weslie, this is the oxygen spray.
Weslie, ini semprotan oksigen.
Spray it on your body and you can breathe under water.
Semprot ke tubuhmu dan kau bisa bernapas dalam air.
It's very chaotic inside a waterspout. Contact us if anything happens.
Sangat kacau di dalam waterspout. Hubungi kami jika terjadi sesuatu.
Okay. Let's go!
Baiklah. Ayo!
My plan worked!
Rencanaku berhasil.
We came to save you!
Kami akan menolongmu.
One, two...
Satu, dua...
three…
tiga!
Come on, give me your hand.
Ayo, berikan tanganmu.
I've finally grouped all my duplicates.
Akhirnya semua duplikatku sudah terkumpul.
Now we shall combine!
Sekarang kita akan bergabung!
Wonderful! I'm back to normal now.
Luar biasa! Aku sudah normal.
Weslie!
Weslie!
Hold on tight!
Pegangan!
Thank goodness you and the sky crystal are both all right.
Untung kau dan kristal langit selamat.
Weslie...
Weslie...
You don't have to thank me.
Tak perlu berterima kasih.
No, I want to say--
Tidak, aku mau bilang...
Really, you don't have to thank me.
Kau tak perlu berterima kasih.
No, I just wanted to ask, if you're here, who is controlling Magic Train?
Tidak, aku mau bertanya, jika kau di sini, siapa yang mengendalikan Kereta Ajaib?
Let's fix Magic Train as soon as we can.
Ayo perbaiki Kereta Ajaib secepatnya.
Luckily, we didn't drive Sirius down here.
Untung tak pakai Sirius kemari.
Weslie, are you all right?
Kau baik-baik saja?
We're fine, but Magic Train is broken.
Kami baik, tapi Kereta Ajaib rusak.
What about the sky crystal?
Kalau kristalnya?
The sky crystal is with me.
Kristal langit ada padaku.
The sky crystal doesn't work underwater.
Kristal langit tak berfungsi di bawah air.
Hurry back up after you've fixed Magic Train.
Cepat naik setelah Kereta Ajaib menyala.
Stay safe!
Jaga dirimu!
With me, Wolffy, around, he is absolutely safe.
Denganku, Wolffy, dia pasti aman.
It's not safe because you're around!
Tak aman karena ada kau!
Is it an earthquake?
Ada gempa bumi?
-Magic Train! -Don't worry about it. Run over there!
- Kereta Ajaib! - Jangan cemaskan itu. Pergi!
Weslie is in danger! We have to go save him.
Weslie terancam. Kita harus menolongnya.
But we don't have Magic Train. How can we get down there?
Tak ada Kereta Ajaib. Bagaimana cara ke sana?
Let's go find Sirius.
Ayo cari Sirius.
Luckily, we ran away quickly.
Untung kita cepat kabur.
Is anyone here...
Ada orang di sini...
Is someone trapped by the fallen rocks?
Ada orang terjebak oleh batu jatuh?
Come on, let's go in and take a look.
Ayo masuk dan lihat.
Magic Train is damaged!
Kereta Ajaib rusak!
Are Weslie and Wolffy all right?
Apa Weslie dan Wolffy baik-baik saja?
Weslie!
Weslie!
Weslie, where are you?
Weslie, di mana kau?
Wolffy! Weslie and Wolffy aren't in here.
Wolffy!
Wolffy...
Wolffy...
Mom, has Dad gone missing?
Ibu, apa Ayah menghilang?
No. Dad is just playing hide-and-seek with us.
Tidak. Ayah hanya main petak umpet dengan kami.
Then I can surely find Dad.
Aku pasti bisa menemukan Ayah.
They should be around here.
Mereka pasti ada di sekitar sini.
Then we'll go and find them.
Kami akan pergi mencari mereka.
Chief, please stay here and wait for news.
Pak Kepala, tetap di sini dan tunggu kami.
Okay, I'll stay behind to fix Magic Train just in case.
Baik, aku tetap di sini memperbaiki Kereta Ajaib untuk jaga-jaga.
We'll go and find them too.
Kita cari juga.
It's too dangerous underwater. You two should stay here.
Di bawah air terlalu berbahaya. Kalian jangan pergi.
Yes. We can't afford to lose Willie while we're trying to find Wolffy.
Ya. Jangan sampai Willie hilang saat sedang mencari Wolffy.
All right.
Baiklah.
They're not here.
Mereka tak ada di sini.
They're not here either.
Di sini juga tak ada.
I've searched over there, but can't find them either.
Aku cari di sana tapi tak ketemu.
Weslie!
Weslie!
I'm here!
Aku di sini!
It's Weslie's voice!
Itu suara Weslie!
It seems to have come from the cave.
Tampaknya berasal dari dalam gua.
Weslie!
Weslie!
I'm here!
Aku di sini!
Weslie's here!
- Weslie! - Kalian datang!
Why are you trapped?
- Kenapa kau terkurung? - Kami akan menolongmu.
Weslie, are you all right?
Weslie, kau tak apa-apa?
I'm fine.
Aku baik.
There are traps here. Be careful, everyone.
Ada jebakan di sini. Hati-hati, Semua.
Then let's get out of here immediately.
Ayo kita pergi dari sini.
Stay close and don't lose anyone.
Selalu rapat dan jangan terpisah.
Can't you see such a handsome wolf here?
Kau tak melihat ada serigala tampan di sini?
I forgot Wolffy is here too.
Aku lupa Wolffy juga di sini.
You're not that bad after all.
Kau tak terlalu payah.
Wolnie and Willie came too. Let's get out of here quickly.
Wolnie dan Willie juga datang. Cepat keluar dari sini.
Willie, Dad's coming!
Willie, Ayah datang!
Wolffy, you're running too fast.
Wolffy, kau lari terlalu cepat.
Can't you see such a cute fish here?
Kau tak bisa lihat ikan imut di sini?
Oh, right, there's a little fish too.
Benar, ada ikan kecil juga.
Right, why were you trapped here?
Kenapa kau terjebak di sini?
Weslie and I heard a voice, so we went into the cave.
Weslie dan aku mendengar suara, jadi kami pergi ke gua.
We found this little fish trapped inside.
Kami menemukan ikan kecil ini terperangkap.
I went to save him because I'm kind and ended up trapped with Weslie.
Aku pergi menyelamatkannya karena baik dan terjebak dengan Weslie.
I went into the cave to hide from the falling rocks,
Aku masuk gua untuk sembunyi dari batu jatuh,
then a dark shadow passed behind me,
lalu ada bayangan gelap di belakangku, lalu aku terjebak perangkap.
A dark shadow?
Bayangan gelap?
I'm finally done fixing Magic Train.
Akhirnya Kereta Ajaib sudah bagus.
Mommy, I see Dad.
Ibu, aku melihat Ayah.
This must be the data recorder of Magic Train.
Ini pasti perekam data Kereta Ajaib.
Hold on.
Tunggu.
Did he cause the rocks to fall?
Apa dia penyebab batu jatuhnya?
Village Chief.
Kepala Desa.
Children, glad to know you're all right.
Anak-anak, syukurlah kalian baik-baik saja.
Weslie, you have to be careful!
Weslie, kau harus hati-hati!
That fish might be a villain.
Ikan itu mungkin penjahat.
Weslie...
Weslie...
Weslie! Little fish, what are you doing?
Weslie! Ikan kecil, apa yang kau lakukan?
Little fish?
Ikan kecil?
Who told you I'm a fish?
Siapa yang bilang aku ikan kecil?
Oh, no, I'm stuck... Give me a little time.
Aku tersangkut! Tunggu sebentar.
This is...
- Dia... - Orang awan hitam?
I've been lying low among you for a long time.
Aku telah lama mengamati kalian.
The video camera on Magic Train,
Kamera video di Kereta Ajaib,
the note picked up by Mechanical Bird, I did all that.
catatan yang diambil Burung Mekanik, itu semua ulahku.
In order to get the sky crystal,
Demi kristal langit, aku bahkan memancingmu masuk ke dalam air.
But I didn't expect you to escape from the falling rocks.
Tapi aku tak mengira kau lari dari batu jatuhnya.
I see. You pretended to be trapped and lured us into the cave.
Kau pura-pura terjebak dan memancing kami ke gua.
No. Actually, I wanted to lure you into the cave.
Tidak. Sebenarnya, aku ingin memancingmu ke dalam gua.
When you came close to me, I would press the red button and trap you.
Saat kau mendekatiku, aku tekan tombol merah dan menjebakmu.
But there's dirt on such a perfect remote control!
Tapi ada kotoran di pengendaliku!
I can't let that happen.
Itu tak bisa kubiarkan.
I pressed the wrong button!
Aku salah tekan tombol.
So I modified my plan and continued to lure you.
Jadi, aku memodifikasi rencanaku dan terus memancingmu.
I'm here!
Aku di sini!
Someone's trapped. We'll save you.
Ada yang terperangkap! Kami akan menolongmu.
I intended to trap you after you saved me.
Aku ingin menjebakmu setelah kau menyelamatkanku.
However, I left a thread on the remote control when I wiped it.
Namun, ada seutas tali pengendaliku setelah aku seka.
We're trapped too.
Kami terjebak juga.
That is how we all ended up being trapped.
Itu sebabnya kita semua terjebak.
It doesn't matter anymore because I've got the sky crystal!
Itu tak penting lagi karena aku punya kristal langit!
-What do you need the sky crystal for? -I'm going to destroy it.
- Untuk apa kristal langit itu? - Aku akan menghancurkannya.
That is my gem. I won't let you destroy it.
Itu permataku. Aku takkan membiarkanmu merusaknya.
Give it back to me.
Kembalikan!
Let's help Wolffy.
Bantu Wolffy.
I caught him.
Aku menangkapnya.
Really?
Sungguh?
You can't escape. Give in now.
Kau tak bisa kabur. Menyerahlah.
I won't give in easily.
Aku takkan mudah menyerah.
Goodbye, everyone!
Selamat tinggal, Semua!
Don't go!
Jangan pergi!
Children...
Anak-anak...
Are you all right?
Kalian baik-baik saja?
Village Chief, the sky crystal was taken. Let's hurry and get it back.
Kepala Desa, kristal langitnya direbut. Harus kita kejar.
Wolnie, Willie, this place is too dangerous. Let's get out of here.
Wolnie, Willie, tempat ini berbahaya. Ayo pergi dari sini.
Wolffy, aren't you going to help us chase the villain?
Wolffy, kau takkan membantu kami mengejarnya?
I don't get myself involved in dangerous things like that.
Aku tak melibatkan diri dalam hal-hal berbahaya.
I'm taking my wife and son away from this dangerous place.
Aku membawa istri dan putraku pergi dari tempat ini.
In that case, we'll chase the villain ourselves.
Kalau begitu, kita kejar penjahat itu sendiri.
Okay.
Baiklah.
TO BE CONTINUED
BERSAMBUNG